Finding aid for Marvin Lemmon Niehuss Papers, 1923-1972 (bulk 1941-1968)
Bentley Historical Library
- Topical Files, 1923-1972
  - 1966-1967
    - Act No. 128 (Box 19)
    - Act No. 245 (Box 19)
    - Administrative Office Building (Box 19)
    - Admissions (Box 19)
    - Alumni Association (Box 19)
    - American Association of University Professors (Box 19)
    - American Council on Education (Box 19)
    - Architecture and Design, College of (Box 19)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Site (Box 19)
    - Brazil (Box 19)
    - Business Administration, School of (Box 19)
    - C (Box 19)
    - Center for the Study of Higher Education (Box 19)
    - Chrysler Corporation (Box 19)
    - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (Box 19)
    - Conflict of Interest (Box 19)
    - Cross, R.N. (Box 19)
    - Cutler, Richard (Box 19)
    - D (Box 19)
    - Dearborn Campus (Box 19)
    - E (Box 19)
    - Education, Department of (Box 19)
    - Education, Higher--Conference (Box 19)
    - Engineering College (Box 19)
    - Faxon (Box 19)
    - Fees (Box 19)
    - Flint College (Box 19)
    - G (Box 19)
    - German House (Box 19)
    - Gifts (Box 19)
    - Graduate School (Box 19)
    - Great Lakes Basin Commission (Box 19)
    - H (Box 19)
    - Health, Education and Welfare (Box 19)
    - Highway Safety Research Institute (Box 19)
    - Hildebrandt, H.W. (Box 19)
    - Honorary Degrees, Committee on (Box 19)
    - Hospital Administration, Bureau of (Box 19)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee (Box 19)
    - Indirect Cost (Box 20)
    - J (Box 20)
    - K (Box 20)
    - Kellogg Foundation (Box 20)
    - L (Box 20)
    - Legislators (Box 20)
    - Literary College Faculty Code (Box 20)
    - Lutheran University Hospital (Box 20)
    - M (Box 20)
    - Master Plan (Box 20)
    - Medical School (Box 20)
    - Michigan Daily (Box 20)
    - Michigan Health Council (Box 20)
    - Michigan Hospital Service (Box 20)
    - Michigan State University (Box 20)
    - Norman, A.G. (Box 20)
    - Nu Sigma Nu Fraternity (Box 20)
    - O (Box 20)
    - P (Box 20)
    - Pierpont, W.K. (Box 20)
    - Plant Extension Committee (Box 20)
    - Polley, Ira (Box 20)
    - Population Studies Center (Box 20)
    - Presidents, Council of, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - President's Commission (Box 20)
    - R (Box 20)
    - Radock, Michael (Box 20)
    - Reed Report--Student Affairs (Box 20)
    - Regents (Box 20)
    - Residential College (Box 20)
    - Role Committee (Box 20)
    - Romney, George (Box 20)
    - S (Box 20)
    - Senate, University (Box 20)
    - Slee, Vergil N. (Box 20)
    - Smith, Allan (Box 20)
    - Solo, Robert (Box 20)
    - State Board of Education (Box 20)
    - Student Affairs (Box 20)
    - T (Box 20)
    - Television (Box 20)
    - Tropical Studies, Center for (Box 20)
    - University Hospital (Box 20)
    - W (Box 20)
  - Special Advisory Committee to the President on the Cases of Clement Markert, Mark Nickerson, and H. Chandler Davis, 1954 (Box 21)
  - Deanship Search File--Literary College, 1950-1951 (Box 21)
  - Deanship Search File
    - Business Administration, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
    - Dental School, 1961-1962 (Box 22)
    - Education, 1951-1952 (Box 22)
    - Engineering, 1957-1958 (Box 22)
    - Architecture, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
    - Music, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
    - Natural Resources, 1961-1962 (Box 22)
    - Public Health, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
    - Medical School, 1958-1959 (Box 22)
  - 55 Million Dollar Fundraising Program File (Box 22)
  - Phoenix Project File (Box 23)
  - Sesquicentennial File (Box 23)
  - 1923-1971
    - Advisory Committee on University Policies, 1941-1948; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - American Association of University Professors [re: alleged communists on faculty], 1954-1956 (Box 24)
    - "Analysis of Degrees Granted 1961-62 and 1963-64,", 1967 (Box 24)
    - Appropriation Requests to Legislature, 1947-1961; 23 folders (Box 24)
    - Appropriation Requests to Legislature, 1961-1968; 10 folders (Box 25)
    - Appropriation Senate Hearing and Budget Information, 1968 (Box 25)
    - Budget Requests and Estimates, 1948/49 (Box 25)
    - Building Modernization-Request to the Legislature, 1950/51 (Box 25)
    - "Building Needs at Michigan Colleges of Education,", 1949 (Box 25)
    - Building Program Proposal, 1937 (Box 25)
    - "Buildings and Grounds Operation and Maintenance," study by J.C. Christensen, 1925 (Box 25)
    - Capital Outlay, 1945-1957; 4 folders (Box 25)
    - Cash Crisis-clippings and notes, 1957-1968 (Box 25)
    - Class Size-statistics and reports [incomplete], 1949-1958 (Box 25)
    - Communism, 1947-1953 (Box 25)
    - Control Data, 1946-1962; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Editorials and clippings, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Employee Statistics, 1945-1961 (Box 25)
    - Enrollment Counts and Projections, 1949-1964 (Box 25)
    - Enrollment Statistics, 1923-1950; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Enrollment Statistics, 1954-1959 (Box 26)
    - Faculty Economic Status, 1928-1955 (Box 26)
    - Faculty Economic Status Reports [incomplete], 1948-1971 (Box 26)
    - Faculty Salary Statistics and Comparisons [incomplete], 1938-1965; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Faculty Work Load, 1946-1960 (Box 26)
    - Fire Hazards, 1951 (Box 26)
    - Foreign Students, 1945-1961 (Box 26)
    - Freshman Admissions, 1949-1962 (Box 26)
    - Fundraising, circa 1923/24 (Box 26)
    - Instructional Costs, 1947-1954 (Box 26)
    - Legislative Appropriation Requests-notes, 1949-1967; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Legislative Correspondence, 1930-1933; 1955; 1967; 5 folders (Box 26)
    - Legislature, 1944-1949; 4 folders (Box 26)
    - Little, Clarence Cook, 1925-1927 (Box 26)
    - Michigan State College Name Change, 1954 (Box 26)
    - Operations Budget, 1954-1956; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Plant Extension Committee, 1945-1949; 1966; 4 folders (Box 27)
    - Proposed Bonding Plan, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Research Demands on Faculty, 1959-1962 (Box 27)
    - Research Funding Request, 1953 (Box 27)
    - Scholarships and Fellowships, 1947-1956 (Box 27)
    - "Selected Characteristics of the Faculty of the University of Michigan,", 1959 (Box 27)
    - Space Utilization, 1948/49 (Box 27)
    - Special Advisory Committee [re: alleged communists on faculty], 1954; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Student Credit Hour Statistics, 1947-1965 (Box 27)
    - Student-Teacher Ratio, 1929-1966 (Box 27)
    - University Organization and Administrative Patterns, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
  - 1929-1972
    - Academic Freedom, 1956-1966 (Box 28)
    - Academic Freedom and Tenure, 1969 (Box 28)
    - Admissions, 1968
      [Student records restricted until July 01, 2053 ]
    - Alumni Fund, 1943 (Box 28)
    - Alumni Lists, 1966 (Box 28)
    - American Association of University Professors (AAUP)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 28)
      - Ralph Fuchs, 1954-1956 (Box 28)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)--Louis Joughin, 1957 (Box 28)
    - American Council on Education, Denver, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Anti-Riot Provisions, 1968-1969 (Box 28)
    - Appointment Procedure, 1954-1955 (Box 28)
    - Auditor General's Report, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Autonomy of the University
      - 1961-1967 (Box 28)
      - Coordination, 1963-1969 (Box 28)
      - Michigan State Board of Education--Constitutional Powers, 1964-1966 (Box 28)
    - William Beaumont Hospital, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Biederman, Les, 1956 (Box 28)
    - Brazilian Program (College of Engineering), 1966 (Box 28)
    - Campus as a Public Place, undated (Box 28)
    - Center for Tropical Studies (proposed), Tehuantepec, Mexico, 1957-1958 (Box 28)
    - Chambers, M.M., 1967 (Box 28)
    - Chinese Graduate List, 1955-1956 (Box 28)
    - Classified Research, 1967-1968 (Box 28)
    - Community Relations (Detroit Commission on), 1960-1968 (Box 28)
    - Compact on Education, 1967 (Box 28)
    - Compliance Review (Discrimination), 1966-1968 (Box 28)
    - Conductron Corporation (Keeve M. Siegel), 1967 (Box 28)
    - Endowments--Subjects for, 1945-1948 (Box 28)
    - Equal Opportunity Employment Compliance Review, 1967 (Box 28)
    - Evaluation of Faculty, 1940-1969 (Box 28)
    - Experiments on Human Beings--Legal Problems, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Federal Relations--American Council on Education, 1962 (Box 28)
    - President Fleming, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Fraternities and Sororities (Student Government Council), 1956-1963; undated (Box 28)
    - Fund Raising, 1946-1953 (Box 28)
    - Fund Raising at Other Institutions, 1955 (Box 28)
    - General Motors Meeting, 1965 (Box 28)
    - Gifts, 1967-1968 (Box 28)
    - Goldman vs. Olson--Investigating Committee, c.1969 (Box 28)
    - Hair, Dress and Student Discipline, 1968-1969 (Box 28)
    - Huber Committee (State of Michigan Senate Committee to Investigate Campus Disorders and Student Unrest), 1969-1970 (Box 28)
    - Hyma, Professor Albert, 1945-1958 (Box 28)
    - Industrial Health (Institute of), 1967-1968 (Box 28)
    - Institutional Property (Sale of), c.1969 (Box 28)
    - Investigating Committees, 1969 (Box 28)
    - Land Deeds (Washtenaw and Leelenau Counties)
      - Correspondence, 1936-1939; undated (Box 28)
      - Conveyancing, 1940; 1942 (Box 29)
    - Law School
      - 1952-1957 (Box 29)
      - 1960-1967 (Box 29)
    - Lawyers Club, [c.1968] (Box 29)
    - Lawyers Club Rehabilitation--Fund Raising Proposals, 1968-1970 (Box 29)
    - Legal Problems of Higher Education Seminar
      - 1969-1972, undated (Box 29)
      - "Who Runs the University?", 1969 (Box 29)
    - Legislature, 1968-1970 (Box 29)
    - Letters of Congratulations, 1951 (Box 29)
    - The John and Mary Markle Foundation, 1962-1969 (Box 29)
    - Michigan Constitution--Conflict of Interest and other Legal Materials, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Michigan Health Council Telecast, 1963 (Box 29)
    - Migration of College Students, 1938-1964; undated (Box 29)
    - National Foundation for Higher Education, 1971 (Box 29)
    - Out-of-State Students, 1931-1968 (Box 29)
    - Personal, 1955-1969 (Box 29)
    - Dr. Pollock Prize, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Professional and Hospital Activities (Commission of), 1967-1968 (Box 29)
    - Program in Foreign and Comparative Law Proposal, undated (Box 29)
    - Property Course
      - Examination Questions, 1969-1972 (Box 29)
      - Outlines, 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Public Relations (University Committee on)
      - From Dr. James Bruce, 1929-1933 (Box 29)
      - 1931-1940 (Box 29)
      - 1945-1956 (Box 29)
    - Regents, 1956-1957; 1967 (Box 29)
    - Research Funds (House Resolution #114), 1967 (Box 29)
    - Rights and Responsibilities of the Faculty (Committee on the), 1971 (Box 29)
    - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA), 1967 (Box 29)
    - State Income Tax, 1967-1968 (Box 29)
    - Stricklin vs. Regents of the University of Wisconsin (Student Discipline), 1969 (Box 29)
    - Suggested Clauses for Gifts and Bequests to the University, 1955; undated (Box 29)
    - Ten Year Plan, 1938-1948 (Box 29)
    - Tenure, 1968-1972 (Box 29)
    - Trustees--Role and Work, 1962-1968 (Box 29)
    - University Hospital, 1968 (Box 29)
    - University of the Philippines, 1954-1955 (Box 29)
    - Unpublished Articles, 1968 (Box 29)